Tom Gehrels Papers, 1894-2011 (bulk 1961-2000)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series III: Scholarly Files
  - Subseries 1: Articles, talks, lectures, presentations and 1 Interview, 1958-2000
    - Photometric astronomy - computerized, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Photometric studies of Asteroids VIII. Additional photographic magnitudes, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Photometric studies of asteroids IX. Additional light curves, circa 1961 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Physical parameters of asteroids and interrelations with comets, Nobel Symposia, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Peace, progress and human rights 1st International Andre Sakharov Congress, May 21-25, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Photopolarimetry of planets, I.A.U. Symposium, September 1973 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - The Physics and Identity of dark energy, January 2001 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Pioneer results on Ganymede, August 1974 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Polarimetry from high altitude, International Conference on the Utilization of Balloons for Scientific Research, CNES, July 1967 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Polarization of Blue Skys draft, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Polarization Papers I and II no papers just notes and correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Polariscope papers, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Poles of Jupiter calculations and correspondence, 1960-1968 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Practice for Flandrau and Hehru Planetarium, November 1982 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - The Ratio of interstellar polarization to extinction very rough draft, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Scanner-scopy, a new discipline of electronic sky survey preliminary draft, June 26, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Some of my impressions of India, spring 1986 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Satellites and Venus draft, June 27, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - The Spacewatch experience, International Seminar Erice Italy, The Collision of an asteroid or comet with Earth, April, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Spacewatch scientific endeavor, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Spacewatch scientific endeavor, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Survival through Evolution from multiverse to modern society, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Tucson Revised Index of Asteroid data – Triad, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - The Two types of atmosphere of Jupiter and Saturn – College Park Colloquia on chemical evolution, chemical evolution for the giant planets, October 23-26, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - U-V Moon opposition effect-Mercury, 1969-1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - The U.S. pioneering and exploring – AAAS meeting, circa 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization. Negative polarization at small phase angles, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization III. The Lunar surface – drafts, tables, references, correspondence, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization III. The Sunlit blue sky, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization V. Earthlight depolarization – draft, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization VII: Molecular scattering at the skin of interstellar particles, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization IX. Poles of Jupiter, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization XII. Red variables, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization XIII. Interstellar extinction and polarizations, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization XVI. Atmosphere of Jupiter, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization XX. The Integrated disk of the moon, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization XXII. A Reconnaissance of circular polarization, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization XXV. Interstellar polarization from 0.22 to 2.2 um, 1971-1973 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization XXXIII. Venus, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization XXXIII – figures, graphs,photos (no paper). Venus, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - The Wavelength dependence of polarization XXXV. The Planet Mercury, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - What Darwin might have added, if he had lived today, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Published articles, 1958-1965 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Interview with Kelly Beatty from Skye and Telescope, October 15, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 2: Presentations, 1970-1998
    This subseries is arranged chronologically by year.
    - Presentations, 1970-1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Presentations, 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Presentations, 1991-1998 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 3: Conferences, Workshops, meetings, etc., 1965-2995
    - Interstellar Grains Colloquium, Troy, New York, August 24-26, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Effects of a National Space Program on Universities, University of Denver Colloquium, April 4-5, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 1st meeting of the Planetary Astronomy Division of American Astronomical Society, Austin, Texas, December 10,1968 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Solar particles and radiations monitoring organizations, June 26-28, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Toro asteroid meeting,Tucson,AZ, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Committee for space research (Cospar) Plenary 19th meeting, June 8-19, 1976 (no paper) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Asteroid Conference, Tucson, AZ, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Near Earth asteroids, San Juan Capistrano, June 30-July 3, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - International Astronomical Union General Assembly Symposium, no. 150, On the Astro-chemistry of cosmic phenomena, Brazil, August 3-7, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Hazards due to comets and asteroids, Tucson, AZ, January 4-9, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Seventy five years of Hirayama collisional families: Past, present and future, November 29-December 3, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Workshop on meteorites, asteroids and planets, Physical Research Laboratory, November 29-December 3, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - 20 years that changed the world, 1985-2005, March 4-6, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 4: Books written by Dr. Gehrelse, 1974-2005
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by title.
    - The Atoms within us and the origin of thought - correspondence and contract, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Early origin of Species – correspondence and reviews, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Future of humanity - correspondence, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - On the glassy sea an astronomer’s view - draft, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - On the glassy sea an astronomer’s view, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Our finest hour, with nature revealing what we can to make this the greatest century yet, pages 1 – 131, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Our natural inheritance and global responsibility-draft, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Planets, stars and nebulae studies with photopolarimetry, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - The Universe and humanity: Origin and future, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - The Universe and humanity: A worldwide view, 1998-2002 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - The Universe and humanity: A worldwide view - correspondence, 1998-2002 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Universe and humanity: A worldwide view - draft, 1998-2002 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 5: Book chapters, 1968-1979
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by chapter title.
    - Photometry of Asteroids in Surfaces and interiors of planets and satellites“, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - History surveys techniques and future work,The Asteroids, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Photopolarimetry of planets and stars in Vistas in astronomy, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - The Results of the imaging photopolarmeter on Pioneers 10 and 11 Jupiter, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Jupiter, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 6: Book Reviews by Tom Gehrels, 1994-2006
    - Wernher von Braun a crusader for space: a biographical memoir, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Wernher von Braun a crusader for space: a biographical memoir, 1996-2006 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous book reviews, 1996-2006 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 7: Space Science Series
    - Proposal for a Space Science Series, circa 1980 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Space Science Series, 1977-1980 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Space Science Series, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Space Science Series, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Space Science Series, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Space Science Series, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Space Science Series, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Research Files, 1920-2006.
  Research files are divided into 10 subseries all have the involvement of Dr. Gehrels: NASA; 1. Jet Proposal Laboratory; 2. National 3. Geographic Society; 4. National Science Foundations; 5. Office of Naval Research; 6. United States Air Force; 7. other agencies; 8. observations; 9. subject files; 10. Spacewatch.
  - Subseries 1: National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), 1962-1991
    - General, 1962-1969 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Polarimetry of Venus, 1961-1963 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Proposals for photometer telescopes on space vehicles, 1961-1963 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Photopolarimetry of Mars on Voyager, 1961-1967 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Development and testing of a photopolarmeter for space vehicles, 1962-1968 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Proposal for a general purpose telescope on board the Gemini and Apollo spacecraft, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Stellar photometry and polarimetry at wavelengths shorter than 3000A, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Laboratory experiments and reductions of photometry and polarimetry, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Mariner polarimeter, 1963-1966 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - The Wavelength dependence of interstellar polarization, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Arizona photopolarimeter – telescope (APT) orbiting astronomical, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Arizona photopolarimeter – telescope (APT) orbiting astronomical-Experiment description, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Photopolarimetry of Mars on Voyager, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Photometry and polarimetry of bright stars and other selected objects, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Planetary polarimetry, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Infrared spectrometry of Mars, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Institutional grant Tumanoc shelter, circa 1967 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Precision photometry and polarimetry the Marian Dish from an orbiting spacecraft, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Orbiting Astronomical Observatory Project, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Photopolarmetry for geologic mapping of the lunar surface, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Photometry and polarimetry of minor planets, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Ultraviolet spectrometer and telescope for an orbiting astronomic explorer, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - 2nd Orbiting astronomical observatory, 1968-1971 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Lunar surface holography, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Polarimetry, photometry and imaging experiment for the Pioneer F/G Asteroid - Jupiter Mission, appendices, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Polarimetry, photometry and imaging experiment for the Pioneer F/G Asteroid - Jupiter mission, Technical Proposal, May 1969 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Polarimetry, photometry and imaging experiment for the Pioneer F/G Asteroid - Jupiter mission, management proposal, May 1969 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Pioneer meeting notes, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Grand Tour Mission - photopolarimetry team - proposal, January, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Grand Tour Mission - photopolarimetry team meetings, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Grand Tour Mission final technical report, May 1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Grand Tour Mission final technical report, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Development of new photometric techniques, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Jupiter data control, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Photometry of emission line stars with peculiar interstellar polarization, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - A Proposal for a 122-cm Schmidt telescope in the Tucson area, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Galactic light studies, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Solar system photopolarimetry, 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Imaging photopolarimeter experiment in modes 3 and 4 - final report, November to January 1981 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Small planets, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Statistics and photometry of small bodies in the solar system, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Sizes and shapes of asteroids from a combination of photometry with speckle interferometry, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Prostars and planets, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Pole orientation Sidereal period and sense of rotation of asteroids (1 of 2), 1984-1987 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Pole orientation Sidereal period and sense of rotation of asteroids (1 of 2), 1986-1989 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Physical studies of small asteroids and cometary cores, 1986-1989 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Targeted search committee membership, particularly for signals from the direction to which Pioneer and Voyager, 1988-1991 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 2: Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL), 1972, 1991
    - A Proposal for a MJS photometer-polarimeter investigation, August 28,1972 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Neptune and Triton, Voyager project, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 3: National Geographic Society (NGS), 1980-1991
    - Study of asteroid topography, 1980-1982 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - A CCD search for satellites of asteroids, 1984-1986, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 4: National Science Fountain (NSF), 1961-1993
    - The Study of diffuse radiation within planetary atmospheres, 1961-1963 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Polariscope program, 1962-1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Wavelength dependence of intrinsic polarizations, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Project polariscope, 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Project polariscope, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Support to Santa Barbara Research Center on the study for spin- scan imaging for outer planet missions, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Travel grant to Moscow, lectures on Jupiter, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Astronomical polarimetry, 1978-1981 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Astronomical polarimetry, 1981-1983 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - A short description of the MINIPOL photopolarimeter, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Indian rubee fund, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Planetary Occultation observations, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - A Reflector to develop and execute the techniques of fast sky surveying with charge couple devices, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Travel support of foreign scientists to attend six Space Science Series book conferences, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Computer Enhancements to optimize real time detection of earth approaching asteroids, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Investigation of astronomical data pertaining to extinction and polarization, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 5: Office of Naval Research (ONR), 1958-1961
    - Photometry of Asteroids, the moon, planets, and reflection nebulae, 1958-1961 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - The Photometry of the planets, 1962-1968 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous grants/proposals, 1958-1963 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 6: United States Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratories, 1964-1986
    - Photometry and polarimetry of minor planets, 1964-1967 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - CCD analysis system to locate dim space targets, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 7: Other agencies, 1958-1995
    - Photometric studies of asteroids VII. photographic magnitudes, 1949-1958 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Photopolarimetry of reflection nebulae, radio galaxies and quasars, Steward Observatory, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Proposals dedicated to studies of the near earth environment, the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Asteroids near earth, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - American Institute of Indian Studies, circa 1979 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - A Scanning facility for solar system surveys, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Solar System Studies, 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Indo-United States in CCD scanning for comets and asteroids, 1989-1995 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Space Guard, Strategic Defense imitative (SID), 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Proposal for an Institute for Space Environmental Studies (ISES) at the University of Arizona, undated (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Proposal for the construction of an astronomical telescope of the central Plateau of Sri Lanka, undated (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Proposal for a program of studies of small solid bodies in space, undated (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - NOVAE search project, undated (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Subseries 8: Observations
    - Asteroid phase functions, undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Asteroid polarimetry, 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Data 166 – Comp stars – JM Standards - Mass ALIA, circa 1958 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - General Observations, 1920-1999 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - General observations, 1920-1999 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Glass prints, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Lunar regions, circa 1956-1961 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Massalia program, McDonald, 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Means and standard errors computed, circa 1973 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - New general catalog NCG 4595, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Observations of selected areas project, 1954-1958 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - OPH program, 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Palomar Hale Observatory, 1964-1978 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Planets polarimetry, circa 1961-1964 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Polariscope flight, See box 28., February 9, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Polarization, circa 1960 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Polarization wavelength being observed, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Saturn and Jupiter observations – old, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Special sequences and instructions to focus the 10” Cook Telescope, circa 1955 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Toro and Eros observations - Mauna Kea, Hawaii, 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - : Venus, September 16, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 9: Subject files, 1954-2004
    - : All India summer school, 2002-2004 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - : Asteroids and comet mission studies, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - : Atlas Milky Way developing, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - : Balloon project, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - :Bibliography – astronomy books and graduate departments, circa 1960 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Burrell Schmidt telescope – survey of planets, 1985-1987 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Calibration – integrated adopted, 1954-1971 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Comet and Asteroid Advisory Mission panel, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Critical list of asteroids, 1954-1958 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Delft Utrecht Balloon experiment, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Early history of Kitt Peak according to the Meinels, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Faint star sequence, circa 1973 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Filters, 1956-1965 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Glossary and bibliography for humanity book, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Ground based gear, circa 1968 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Image processing programs, circa 1972 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - International Astronomical Union (IAU) Commission 15, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Jupiter Mission useful file - notes, 1968-1972 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Jupiter Probe, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Jupiter Probe, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Laboratory photometry and polarimetry measurements of volcanic and surface materials, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Lowell Observatory, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Minipol users and Minipol log books, 1972-1976 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Near Earth objects, 1990-1993 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Photometric studies, 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Pioneer 10 and 11/Jupiter mission, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Pioneer 10 and 11/Jupiter mission, 1974-1975 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Pioneer 10 and 11/Jupiter mission, 1976-1979 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Pioneer, 1980-1983 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Polarimeter Mariner balloon flight mission, 1964-1969 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Polariscope II, 1963-1968 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Programs for MIE scattering in finite cylinders, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Sakharov, Andrei, 1980-1987 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 70” telescope design for Mount Lemon, circa 1970 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - 70” telescope Mount Lemon, radar station, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - 70” telescope, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Spectroscopy flights balloon, circa 1965-1968 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Sri Lanka proposed 40” reflector telescope, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Sri Lanka Observatory project, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Steinheim Crater, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - A Trip through the Laboratory for Astrophysics and Space Research of the University of Chicago, 1962-1967 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Terms of reference for minor planets, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Van Biesbroeck Award, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Uranus Occultation, 1975-1977 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 10: Spacewatch, 1971-1988
    This subseries is arranged chronologically by year. Spacewatch is the name of a group at the University of Arizona's Lunar and Planetary Laboratory founded by Prof. Tom Gehrels and Dr. Robert S. McMillan in 1980. The primary goal of Spacewatch was to explore the various populations of small objects in the solar system, and study the statistics of asteroids and comets in order to investigate the dynamical evolution of the solar system populations. Spacewatch also finds potential targets for interplanetary spacecraft missions, provides follow-up astrometry of such targets, and finds objects that might present a hazard to the Earth.
    - Fund raising letters and mailing lists, 1971-1986 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Spacewatch program, 1977-1981 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Budgets and salaries, 1980-1983 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Prime Focus corrector 71 inch f/2.2 paraboloid (asteroid camera), 1981 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Spacewatch camera, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Spacewatch camera; scanning the sky with the CCD, December 6, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Spacewatch camera - SETS. Inc., 1984 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - The First Spacewatch survey of faint minor planets; an observing plan for, March 1984-1985 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Spacewatch program, 1984-1985 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Spacewatch reports and photographs, 1984-1997 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Spacewatch camera fund raising packet, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Spacewatch 72” telescope, 1990-1994 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Spacewatch program, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Spacewatch program, 1996-1998 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Spacewatch telescope history of the 72” telescope, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Spacewatch general, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 11: Science Notes: chronologically arranged, 1951-1990
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1951-1971 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - : XE, circa, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - : Jupiter poles, circa 1963 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - : Solar System part III, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - : Moon, circa 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - : Instructional polarization, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - : Jupiter paper, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - : TAWU notes, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 20)